<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crystal Seas Kayaking - Guide to the San Juan Islands</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/guide/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 12:31:35 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 12:31:35 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Friday Harbor Day Kayaking Trip</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re visiting the Pacific Northwest, you won’t want to miss out on spending a day on a kayaking trip from Friday Harbor. Nestled in the heart of the San Juan Islands, Friday Harbor offers the perfect location for experiencing the best of the Northwest’s scenery, wildlife, and recreation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/0019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Friday Harbor Day Kayaking Trip&quot; title=&quot;Friday Harbor Day Kayaking Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what you need to know to plan a Friday Harbor day kayaking trip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, you’ll need to make your way to Friday Harbor. Most visitors arrive via ferry from the Anacortes ferry landing, but if you’re coming from the Seattle area, you also have the option of traveling via air with Kenmore Air from SeaTac International Airport or Downtown Seattle or taking the Victoria Clipper directly from Downtown Seattle to Friday Harbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our tour groups meet at Friday Harbor, the take a complimentary shuttle to Snug Harbor for a safety lesson and departure, and then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;spend three hours taking you along the west side of the San Juan Island&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll have the opportunity to see wildlife and learn from our expert guides, who will give you a local perspective on the area with their knowledge of the habitat, wildlife, and surrounding areas. These tours are open to all ages and experience levels, and our team has your safety in mind every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your tour is complete, we provide complimentary transportation back to Friday Harbor, where you’ll have the option to spend some time before returning to your destination. After a long day of paddling and sightseeing, you’ll surely have worked up an appetite and have the chance to enjoy Friday Harbor’s extensive dining options, whether you’re in the mood for lunch, dinner, or drinks. You can then take a ferry back, or extend your stay with accommodations on Friday Harbor or other areas of San Juan Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/0030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Friday Harbor Day Kayaking Trip&quot; title=&quot;Friday Harbor Day Kayaking Trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to expand your trip beyond a kayaking tour, we also offer additional activities and accommodations to help you get the most out of your visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a multiple-day bicycle tour of the island&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goterratrek.com/&quot;&gt;GoTerraTrek.com&lt;/a&gt; and get a new view of the island terrain and the surrounding sound.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book a whale watching tour&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.watchwhales.com/&quot;&gt;WatchWhales.com&lt;/a&gt; for a comfortable experience (including restrooms and a snack bar) that takes you further beyond the island for views of the orcas’ habitats and sweeping scenery. You’ll have the chance to catch a glimpse of orca whales, sea lions, harbor seals, harbor porpoises, Dall’s porpoises, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay overnight at a vacation rental&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sanjuanpm.com/&quot;&gt;SanJuanPM.com&lt;/a&gt;. If you select this option, you’ll also receive a 10% discount on Crystal Seas day tours, a 5% discount on multi-day Crystal Seas tours, and a 15% discount on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.watchwhales.com/&quot;&gt;WatchWhales.com&lt;/a&gt; tours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make the most of your day in the Pacific Northwest with a kayaking tour:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;book a three hour kayaking tour today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, or give us a call at 877-732-7877.&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to guiding you through the best of the San Juan Islands!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/friday-harbor-day-kayaking-trip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/friday-harbor-day-kayaking-trip/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Rentals</category>
        
        <category>Kayaking</category>
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Eco-Friendly Reasons to Try a Sea Kayaking Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking a kayak tour in Puget Sound is an eco-friendly way to see the islands and experience the beauty of the Pacific Northwest without harming the natural environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/DJI_0014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3 Eco-Friendly Reasons to Try a Sea Kayaking Tour&quot; title=&quot;3 Eco-Friendly Reasons to Try a Sea Kayaking Tour&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three eco-friendly reasons to take a kayak tour in the San Juan Islands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit Transportation Needs to Preserve the Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Our kayak tours take place in small groups, which avoids disruption of the terrain and habitats we visit. We also offer free shuttle services from the ferry landing to eliminate the need for guests to bring their own cars onto the island.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore Remote Areas without Leaving a Trace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Kayak tours provide a unique perspective of the San Juan Islands. You’ll have the opportunity to explore areas you can only reach by kayak, which eliminates the need for fuels and other damaging transportation. We’re also dedicated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-multiday-kayak-camping-details.htm&quot;&gt;leaving no trace on our campsites&lt;/a&gt; on our multiple-day camp-to-camp tours.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Small Businesses with Local Conservation Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Our team is proud to support the environment both by hiring knowledgeable and conservation-minded guides and by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-general-why-choose.shtml&quot;&gt;giving back&lt;/a&gt; to wildlife programs and organizations that promote clean air, clean water, and education. We’re thrilled to help educate the public on both habitat restoration and conservation while leading by example through our tours.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/0046.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3 Eco-Friendly Reasons to Try a Sea Kayaking Tour&quot; title=&quot;3 Eco-Friendly Reasons to Try a Sea Kayaking Tour&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience the best of the Pacific Northwest with a kayaking tour:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;book a three hour kayaking tour today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, or give us a call at 877-732-7877.&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to guiding you through the best of the San Juan Islands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plus, if you’re looking for additional excursions beyond a kayaking tour, don’t forget to check out our bicycling tours through&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goterratrek.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;GoTerraTrek.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and whale watching tours through&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.watchwhales.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WatchWhales.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;: make the most of your Pacific Northwest experience with everything the San Juan Islands have to offer!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/3-eco-friendly-reasons-to-try-a-sea-kayaking-tour/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/3-eco-friendly-reasons-to-try-a-sea-kayaking-tour/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Rentals</category>
        
        <category>Kayaking</category>
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Kayak Tour Near Seattle, Washington</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a first-time Seattle visitor or a Pacific Northwest local, there’s no better way to experience the area than with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;kayak tour in the San Juan Islands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/0026.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Best Kayak Tour Near Seattle, Washington&quot; title=&quot;The Best Kayak Tour Near Seattle, Washington&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Crystal Seas, you’ll have a personalized experience with small-group tours departing from Friday Harbor on the San Juan Island. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-about-crystalseas.shtml&quot;&gt;Our team of outdoor enthusiasts&lt;/a&gt; has been guiding kayak tours since 1994, and our history in the area ensures you have the best, most knowledgeable tour guides available. We’re dedicated to continuously educating and challenging ourselves to higher levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our three hour kayaking tours take you along the west side of the San Juan Island, where you have the best chance of seeing wildlife like bald eagles, harbor seals, white tail deer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/guide/2018/04/09/canoing-puget-sound-orcas/&quot;&gt;and (if you’re lucky) orca whales&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To experience one of our kayaking tours, you’ll need to get to Friday Harbor, either via the ferry from Anacortes, Washington, or via Kenmore Air or the Victoria Clipper direct from Seattle. Three hour tours are $99 per person plus tax and tip, and we offer complimentary shuttle pick-up in Friday Harbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/aerial-reef-point-and-turn-island.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Best Kayak Tour Near Seattle, Washington&quot; title=&quot;The Best Kayak Tour Near Seattle, Washington&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unsure about booking a tour, don’t take our word for it—here’s what our guests have said about their Crystal Seas tours:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Being able to see all of the wildlife, seals, otters, and orcas was a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our guide was great, friendly, and interesting, all of our needs were met and we enjoyed it very much! Thank you for a wonderful vacation!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was the best trip I have had in 25 years!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience a once-in-a-lifetime view of the Pacific Northwest with a Crystal Seas kayaking tour.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book a three hour kayaking tour today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, or give us a call at 877-732-7877.&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to guiding you through the best of the San Juan Islands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Red Tricycle for mentioning our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-general-tour-family-custom.htm&quot;&gt;Family Sea Kayaking Tours&lt;/a&gt; on their “&lt;a href=&quot;http://redtri.com/seattle/best-places-to-kayak-with-kids/slide/1&quot;&gt;15 Spectacular Spots to Go Kayaking With Kids&lt;/a&gt;” article.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/the-best-kayak-tour-near-seattle-washington/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/the-best-kayak-tour-near-seattle-washington/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Rentals</category>
        
        <category>Kayaking</category>
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day Trip Kayaking Tours for Seattle Visitors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s your first time visiting Seattle or it’s a frequent destination for your travels, exploring the Puget Sound is a must-do activity for your list. A day trip to Friday Harbor in the San Juan Islands is the perfect addition to your getaway: enjoy the lush scenery, sweeping views, and potential wildlife sightings in one of the most breathtaking locales in the northwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/aerial-off-sanjuan-county-park-kayakers-paddlingcom-size.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sea Kayaking Tours Just North of Seattle Wa&quot; title=&quot;Sea Kayaking Tours Just North of Seattle Wa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our kayaking tours all begin from San Juan Island, and we offer complimentary shuttle pick-up in Friday Harbor. All you have to do is get yourself here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 4 easy ways to get to Friday Harbor from Seattle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the Airporter Shuttle from SeaTac Airport directly to the ferry landing in Anacortes, then walk on the ferry. Ferry walk-ons mean you don’t have to bring your car or wait in line, so we highly recommend this option for easy access during your day trip. (&lt;em&gt;2 hour shuttle trip, 1 hour ferry ride&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drive from Seattle to Anacortes and take the Washington State Ferry. If you’re driving onto the ferry, you can make a reservation in advance to ensure your spot. (&lt;em&gt;2 hour drive, 1 hour ferry ride&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the Victoria Clipper (passenger ferry) from Downtown Seattle. You’ll board in downtown Seattle, and the drop-off location is right in Friday Harbor. (&lt;em&gt;3-3.5 hour trip&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fly with Kenmore Air from downtown Seattle or SeaTac International Airport. This is among the pricier options, but will leave you plenty of time for exploring the island. (&lt;em&gt;40 minute flight&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more information on travel and accommodations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-travel-info.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our three hour kayaking tours take you along the west side of the San Juan Island, where you have the best chance of seeing wildlife like bald eagles, harbor seals, white tail deer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/guide/2018/04/09/canoing-puget-sound-orcas/&quot;&gt;and (if you’re lucky) orca whales&lt;/a&gt;. These tours are also perfect for families with children who want an immersive experience: no experience necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Crystal Seas tour has your safety in mind. Our expert guides begin with a short safety lesson and will inform and entertain as you paddle the coastline of San Juan Island. Three hour tours are $99 per person plus tax and tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience the best of the Pacific Northwest with a sea kayaking tour in the San Juan Islands&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience the best of the area with a kayaking tour:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;book a three hour kayaking tour today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, or give us a call at 877-732-7877.&lt;/strong&gt; We look forward to guiding you through the best of the San Juan Islands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact: Crystal Seas also offers multi-day inn and camping trips where you kayak from island to island staying at local inns and campsites. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-general-our-tours.htm&quot;&gt;View Crystal Seas Kayaking Multi-Day Trips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/day-trip-kayaking-tours-for-seattle-visitors/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/day-trip-kayaking-tours-for-seattle-visitors/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Rentals</category>
        
        <category>Kayaking</category>
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Washington State Sea Kayaking Tours</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Searching for the perfect Washington sea kayaking tours? The San Juan Islands are known for their breathtaking views, temperate climate and exciting wildlife. One of the best ways to experience all that the San Juan Islands have to offer is by taking a kayaking tour. Even beginners can participate in a guided three-hour tour along the coast of San Juan Island with Crystal Seas Kayaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-12-03_17-40-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reef Point, San Juan Islands, WA&quot; title=&quot;Reef Point, San Juan Islands, WA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even choose to end your day by watching the sunset on the water. These shorter tours are perfect for families with children who want to learn about plants and wildlife in the area.  Previous groups have encountered bald eagles, harbor seals and much more of the abundant wildlife that calls the San Juan Islands home. You may even spot a group of Orca Whales!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-12-03_17-33-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kayaking off of San Juan County Park, Washington State&quot; title=&quot;Kayaking off of San Juan County Park, Washington State&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multi-day trips are also available for those who love kayaking and want to see more of the islands. Cycling enthusiasts can get the best of both worlds. Spend one day kayaking along more remote islands and the next biking along quiet roads with sheep filled pastures and charming vineyards.  You won’t want to miss some of the best the lighthouses, lavender farms and local inns that Washington has to offer. On longer tours time is included to explore the town on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-12-03_17-34-35.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Orca whales seen from a Whale Watching Tour in the San Juan Islands, Washington State&quot; title=&quot;Orca whales seen from a Whale Watching Tour in the San Juan Islands, Washington State&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More adventurous groups may choose a multi-day trip that includes camping and personalized gourmet meals. Inexperienced groups and families are welcome on many of the tours. For a unique vantage point of the Washington coast, peaceful beaches and a chance to see aquatic wildlife there is no better way to go island hopping. Every Crystal Seas tour is led by an expert guide to ensure your safety and make sure you don’t miss a thing. For private groups and groups who have specific interests in mind, custom tours are available!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 01:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/washington-state-sea-kayaking-tours/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/washington-state-sea-kayaking-tours/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
        <category>Kayaking</category>
        
        <category>Washington_State</category>
        
        <category>San_Juan_Islands</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>San Juan to Vieques Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is Vieques&lt;/strong&gt; ? Isla de Vieques is a large island approximately 8 miles off the coast of Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-11-13_20-52-39.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does Vieques have a Bioluminescent Bay?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes; Vieques island is known for it’s micro-organism infested Bioluminescent Bay. The luminescence is from a micro-organism named Pyrodinium bahamense and it glows blue when the water is disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/15/2018-11-15_00-15-46\[1\].jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do they have tours running from San Juan to Vieques?&lt;/strong&gt; Kayak tours start from Esperanza; which is a small town with a population of about 1000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How far is it from San Juan to Vieques?&lt;/strong&gt; About 8 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much does a San Juan to Vieques tour cost?&lt;/strong&gt; About $50. We recommend you checkout &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abessnorkeling.com&quot;&gt;Abe’s Snorkeling and Bio-Bay Tours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 01:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/san-juan-to-vieques-tour/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/san-juan-to-vieques-tour/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Maps</category>
        
        <category>Friday_Harbor</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kayak Rental Friday Harbor WA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While it is possible to rent a kayak and paddle around Friday Harbor we do not recommend it as much as we recommend kayaking up or down the west coast of San Juan Island.  Paddling the west side of San Juan Island is where you will have the best chance of seeing local wildlife such as bald eagles, harbor seals, jellyfish, starfish, white tail deer, river otters, and whales (  if you are lucky  ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-12-03_17-37-21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The west side of San Juan Island is home to the Haro Strait Special Management Fishery Area, False Bay San Juan Islands Marine Preserve, Lime Kiln Point State Park, San Juan County Park, Snug Harbor Resort, and many more interesting locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already sea kayaked the south and west side of the island and are ready for a different experience you can rent kayaks from a local outfit named Friday Harbor Marine or call them at 360 378 6202.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck and happy paddling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/guide/uploads/2018/11/15/crystalseas-kayaking-photo-paddlingNEt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 01:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/kayak-rental-friday-harbor-wa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/kayak-rental-friday-harbor-wa/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Rentals</category>
        
        <category>Kayaking</category>
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Canoing Puget Sound Orcas Test</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can one go canoing in the Puget Sound and see Orca?&lt;/strong&gt; The west side of San Juan Islands are a popular spot for whale watchers to see orca. Canoing might be a bit risky because of the inherent instability of a canoe. We recommend a sea kayaking tour instead. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-11-13_21-39-09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much does it cost to go canoing in the Puget Sound to see orca whales?&lt;/strong&gt; There are no outfitters on San Juan Island that rent canoes so you would need to bring your own to the island ( or paddle all the way to San Juan Island ) . Again; we recommend sea kayaking and not canoing. A sea kayaking tour on the west side of San Juan Island runs about $99 for a three hour tour ( plus tax and tip ) per person. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crystalseas.com/cs-sj-tour-3hour.htm&quot;&gt;More details on our three hour sea kayaking tour here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where else in the Puget Sound could we go Canoing to see orca?&lt;/strong&gt; One needs to be very lucky to see orca in a canoe or kayak; they are fast swimmers and cover swim over a hundred miles per day. Orca are known to explore into the deepest bays in the south Puget Sound but this is a rare occurrence. To give yourself and your family the best chance of seeing orca in the wild we recommend a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.watchwhales.com&quot;&gt;whale watching tour with San Juan Excursions&lt;/a&gt; which departs from Friday Harbor on San Juan Island. These whale watching tours are $99 per person plus tax. The have a guarantee where if you don’t see orca whales they will give you a rain check to go out with them again for free. The rain check never expires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stqsfya1eeoulo.dreamhosters.com/2018-11-13_21-40-30.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I stay in a vacation rental in Friday Harbor/San Juan Island will I get a discount on whale watching tours and sea kayaking tours?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes; if you stay at a rental managed by San Juan Property Management you get a coupon for 15% off orca whale watching and 10% off a sea kayaking tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018/11/15/crystalseas-kayaking-photo-paddlingNEt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 01:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guide/canoing-puget-sound-orcas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guide/canoing-puget-sound-orcas/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Canoing</category>
        
        <category>Tours</category>
        
        <category>Washington_State</category>
        
        <category>Friday_Harbor</category>
        
        <category>San_Juan_Islands</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
